A panda.Series can be queried, either by the index position or the index label.
Pandas的Series(列表)可以查詢，使用索引(index)的位置或索引的標籤(label)。
As we saw, if you don't give an index to the series, the position and
正如我們所看到的，如果你不指派series的index，則位置和
the label are effectively the same values.
標籤實際上是相同的值。
To query by numeric location, starting at zero, use the iloc attribute.
要利用數位位置查詢，從零開始，使用iloc屬性。
To query by the index label, you can use the loc attribute.
要通過索引標籤(label)進行查詢，可以使用loc屬性。
Here's an example using national sporting event data from Wikipedia.
以下是維基百科的全國體育賽事數據。
Let's say we want to have a list of all of the sports in our index and
假設我們想要列出所有的運動當我們的索引(index)，和
a list of countries as values.
國家列表作為值(value)。
You might keep these in a dictionary and create a series as we discussed.
你可以將這些保留在dictionary中，並按照我們以前討論的方式創建一個series。
If you wanted to see the fourth country on this,
如果你想查看第四個國家，
we would use the iloc attribute with the parameter 3.
我們將使用iloc屬性和參數,3.
If you wanted to see which country has golf as its national sport,
如果你想了解哪個國家將高爾夫(golf)作為其全國運動，
we would use the loc attribute with parameter golf.
那麼我們將使用loc屬性和參數高爾夫(golf)。
Keep in mind that iloc and loc are not methods, they are attributes.
請記住，iloc和loc不是方法(method)，它們是屬性(attribute)。
So you don't use parentheses to query them, but square brackets instead,
所以你不用括號()來查詢它們，而是使用方括號[]，
which we'll call the indexing operator.
我們稱之為索引運算符。
Though in Python,
在Python中，
this calls get and set an item methods depending on the context of its use.
這叫做獲取(get)和設置(set)一個項目的方法，根據其使用的背景來決定。
This might seem a bit confusing if you're used to languages where encapsulation of
這看起來可能有點困惑的，如果你習慣于語言在哪裡封裝在裏面的
attributes, variables, and properties is common, such as in Java.
屬性、變數和性能是常見的，比如在JAVA中。
Pandas tries to make our code a bit more readable and provides a sort of
Pandas試圖使我們的程式更具有可讀性，並提供一種
smart syntax using the indexing operator directly on the series itself.
智慧語法，使用index操作符直接在series本身。
For instance, if you pass in an integer parameter,
例如，如果你傳入一個整數參數，
the operator will behave as if you want it to query via the iloc attribute.
運算子會表現得好像你想要通過iloc屬性來查詢。
If you pass in an object,
如果你傳入一個物件(object)，
it will query as if you wanted to use the label based loc attribute.
它將認為你想要查詢使用根據標籤(label)的loc屬性。
So what happens if your index is a list of integers?
那麼如果你的index是整數列表會發生什麼呢？
This is a bit complicated, and Pandas can't determine
這有點複雜，pandas無法自動確定
automatically whether you're intending to query by index position or index label.
你是打算通過索引位置或索引標籤進行查詢。
So you need to be careful when using the indexing operator on the series itself.
所以在series本身使用index操作時，你需要小心。
And the safer option is to be more explicit and use the iloc or
而更安全的選擇是更加明確，直接使用
loc attributes directly.
iloc或loc屬性。
Here's an example using some new sports data,
以下是使用一些新的體育數據的範例，
where countries are indexed by integer.
其中國家以整數索引。
If we try and call s sub zero, we get a key error,
如果我們嘗試調用s[0]，我們會得到一個key error，
because there's no item in the sports list with an index of zero.
因為運動列表中沒有任何項目，索引為零。
Instead we have to call iloc explicitly if we want the first item.
相反，如果我們想要第一個項目，我們必須顯式地調用iloc。
Okay, so now we know how to get data out of the series.
好的，現在我們知道如何從series中獲取數據。
Let's talk about working with the data.
我們來談談使用數據。
A common task is to want to consider all of the values inside of a series and
一個常見的工作是想考慮一series內的所有值，
want to do some sort of operation.
我想要做一些運算
This could be trying to find a certain number, summarizing data or
這可能是試圖找到某些數字，總結數據或
transforming the data in some way.
以某種方式轉換數據。
A typical programmatic approach to this would be to iterate over
一個典型的程式設計方法，要遍歷
all the items in the series, and invoke the operation one is interested in.
該series中的所有項目，並調用一個你感興趣的運算
For instance, we could create a data frame of floating point values.
例如，我們可以創建一個浮點值的數據組(dataframe)。
Let's think of these as prices for different products.
讓我們把這些看作是不同產品的價格。
We could write a little routine which iterates over all of the items in
我們可以寫一個小的例行程序碼，遍歷的所有
the series and adds them together to get a total.
series中的項目，並將它們加一起以獲得總數。
This works, but it's slow.
這有效，但速度很慢。
Modern computers can do many tasks simultaneously, especially, but
現代電腦可以同時執行許多任務，
not only, tasks involving mathematics.
尤其是涉及數學的任務。
Pandas and the underlying NumPy libraries support a method of computation called
Pandas和基礎的NumPy程式庫支持一個稱為
vectorization.
向量化
Vectorization works with most of the functions in the NumPy library,
Vectorization與NumPy庫中的大部分功能一起使用，
including the sum function.
包括sum函數。
Here's how we would really write the code using the NumPy sum method.
以下是我們如何使用NumPy sum方法來重寫程式。
First we need to import the numpy module, and then we just call np.sum and
首先我們需要導入numpy程式庫，然後我們調用np.sum
pass in an iterable item.
並傳入一個可遍歷迭代的項目。
In this case, our panda series.
在這裡，我們的pandas series。
Now both of these methods create the same value, but is one actually faster?
現在這兩種方法產生相同的值，但是哪一種是確實更快嗎？
The Jupyter Notebook has a magic function which can help.
Jupyter筆記本有一個神奇的函數，可以幫助。
First, let's create a big series of random numbers.
首先，我們設置一個大系列的隨機(random)數字。
You'll see this used a lot when demonstrating techniques with Pandas.
你會看到使用了很多這種設置，當展示pandas技術時。
Note that I've just used the head method, which reduces the amount of
請注意，我只是用head()的方法，它減少了
data printed out by the series to the first five elements.
列表中印出來的數量到前五個元素的數據。
We can actually verify that length of the series is correct using the len function.
實際上，我們可以驗證序列長度是正確使用len()函數。
Magic functions begin with a percentage sign.
神奇功能以百分比符號%開頭。
If we type this sign and then hit the Tab key,
如果我們打入這個標誌%，然後按Tab鍵，
we can see a list of the available magic functions.
我們可以看到可用的魔術函數的列表。
You could write your own magic functions too, but
你也可以編寫自己的魔術函數
that's a little bit outside of the scope of this course.
但這不過是本課程的範圍之外。
We're actually going to use what's called a cellular magic function.
我們實際上會使用所謂的細胞(cellular)魔術函數
These start with two percentage signs and
這些以兩個百分比的符號開始，
modify a raptor code in the current Jupyter cell.
並修改或包裝當前Jupyter單元中的程式。
The function we're going to use is called timeit.
我們要使用的函數稱為timeit。
And as you may have guessed from the name, this function will run our code a few
你可能已經從名稱猜到了，此函數會運行我們的程式幾次，
times to determine, on average, how long it takes.
來確定，平均而言，它需要多長的時間。
Let's run timeit with our original iterative code.
讓我們運行timeit，用我們原來的反覆運算程式。
You can give timeit the number of loops that you would like to run.
你可以給timeit你希望運行的循環次數。
By default, we'll use 1,000 loops.
預設情況下，我們會使用1,000循環。
I'll ask timeit here to use 100 runs because we're recording this.
我在這裡要求timeit運行100次，因為我們正在錄製這個。
Not bad.
不錯蠻好的
Timeit ran this code and it doesn't seem like it takes very long at all.
Timeit運行這個程式，看起來好像不需要很長的時間。
Now let's try with vectorization.
現在我們來嘗試用向量化(vetorization)。
Wow!
哇!
This is a pretty shocking difference in the speed and
這是一個相當令人震驚的速度差異和
demonstrates why data scientists need to be aware of parallel computing features
展示資料科學家為什麼必須要注意的並行計算的特點
and start thinking in functional programming terms.
並在函數功能編程方面開始思考。
Related feature in Pandas and NumPy is called broadcasting.
在pandas和NumPy的相關的功能稱為廣播(broadcasting)。
With broadcasting, you can apply an operation to every value in the series,
通過broadcasting，你可以對series中的每個值應用操作，
changing the series.
更改series。
For instance, if we wanted to increase every random variable by 2,
例如，如果我們想要對每個隨機變數增加2，
we could do so quickly using the += operator directly on the series object.
我們可以使用+=運算符號直接在列表對像上快速地執行。
Here I'll just use the head operator to just print out the top five rows in
在這裡，我只需要使用head運算印出前五項
the series.
首先，我想要先來介紹這門課的四位講師
The procedural way of doing this would be to iterate through all of
做這的樣程序方式是，遍歷所有的
the items in the series and increase the values directly.
列表中的項目和直接增加它的數值。
A quick aside here.
很快的提一下，
Pandas does support iterating through a series much like a dictionary,
Pandas確實支持遍歷迭代列表項目，很類似於dictionary，
allowing you to unpack values easily.
讓你容易地把數值分拆開。
But if you find yourself iterating through a series,
但如果你發現自己反覆遍歷一列表，
you should question whether you're doing things in the best possible way.
你應該質疑你做的方式是否是盡可能最好的。
Here's how we would do this using the series set value method.
這裡是我們怎麼做這列表的set_value方法。
Let's try and time the two approaches.
讓我們試試這兩種方法，和量它用的時間。
Amazing.
這是令人驚訝的
Not only is it significantly faster, but it's more concise and
不僅是明顯的變快，而它是更簡潔和
maybe even easier to read too.
甚至更容易去讀。
The typical mathematical operations you would expect are vectorized, and the NumPy
你預期的典型數學運算是向量化的，和NumPy
documentation outlines what it takes to create vectorized functions of your own.
文檔概述了創建你自己的向量化的函數所需要怎麼做。
One last note on using the indexing operators to access series data.
最後一點要注意的，在使用索引運算來存取列表資料。
The .loc attribute lets you not only modify data in place, but
.loc屬性(attribute)讓你不僅可以修改數據，
also add new data as well.
還可以添加新數據。
If the value you pass in as the index doesn't exist, then a new entry is added.
如果作為索引傳入的值不存在，則它會添加一個新條目。
And keep in mind, indices can have mixed types.
請記住，指數可以有混合類型。
While it's important to be aware of the typing going on underneath,
雖然重要的是，要注意在下面的類型是什麼，
Pandas will automatically change the underlying NumPy types as appropriate.
Pandas會根據需要，自動更改基本的NumPy類型。
Here's an example using a series of a few numbers.
這是一個使用一列表數字的例子。
We could add some new value, maybe an animal, as you know, I like bears.
我們可以添加一些新的數值，也許是一種動物，如你所知，我喜歡熊。
Just by calling the .loc indexing operator.
然後調用.loc索引操作。
We see that mixed types for data values or index labels are no problem for Pandas.
我們看到數據值或索引標籤的混合類型，對於Pandas來說是沒有問題的。
Up until now I've shown only examples of a series where the index values were unique.
到目前為止，我只顯示了索引值是唯一的
I want to end this lecture by showing an example where index values are not unique,
我想要結束這節課，展示一個索引值不是唯一的例子
and this makes data frames different,
這使得dataframe(資料框)，
conceptually, that a relational database might be.
從概念上講，可能不同於關聯資料庫(database)。
Revisiting the issue of countries and their national sports,
回顧國家和國家體育運動的問題，
it turns out that many countries seem to like this game cricket.
事實證明，很多國家似乎都喜歡這個板球比賽。
We go back to our original series on sports.
我們回到我們原來的運動列表。
It's possible to create a new series object with multiple entries for
可以創建一個帶有多個條目的新列表，用
cricket, and then use append to bring these together.
板球索引，然後使用append將它們放在一起。
There are a couple of important considerations when using append.
使用append時，有幾個重要的注意事項。
First, Pandas is going to take your series and
首先，Pandas將採取你的列表，
try to infer the best data types to use.
並嘗試推斷使用最好的數據類型。
In this example, everything is a string, so there's no problems here.
在這個例子中，一切都是字符(string)，所以這裡沒有問題。
Second, the append method doesn't actually change the underlying series.
其次，append方法實際上並沒有改變底層的列表。
It instead returns a new series which is made up of the two appended together.
而是返回一個由兩個附加在一起組成的新列表。
We can see this by going back and printing the original series of values and
我們可以回溯並列印原始列表值，
seeing that they haven't changed.
看到它們沒有改變。
This is actually a significant issue for
這是實際上的一個重大問題
new Pandas users who are used to objects being changed in place.
新的Pandas使用者，之前習慣了物件(objects)在原處更改。
So watch out for it, not just with append but with other Pandas functions as well.
所以要當心了，不只是append，還有其他的Pandas函數功能。
Finally, we see that when we query the appended series for those who have cricket
最後，我們看到，當我們查詢附加在一起的列表，用板球
as their national sport, we don't get a single value, but a series itself.
作為國家運動的，我們不是得到一個單一的值，而是一個列表。
This is actually very common, and
這實際上是很常見的，
if you have a relational database background, this is very similar to
如果你有資料庫背景，這與表查詢非常
every table query resulting in a return set which itself is a table.
相似，返回集本身也是一個表(table)。
In this lecture,
在這堂課，
we focused on one of the primary data types of the Pandas library, the series.
我們專注於Pandas函數庫的主要數據類型之一，列表(series)。
There are many more methods associated with this series object that we haven't
有更多的方法(methods)與列表(series)有關聯，我們還沒有
talked about.
談到。
But with these basics down, we'll move on to talking about
但這些基礎下，我們會繼續進一步談到
the Panda's two-dimensional data structure, the data frame.
Pandas的二維數據結構，數據框(dataframe)。
The data frame is very similar to the series object, but
dataframe是非常相似於列表(series)，但
includes multiple columns of data, and is the structure that you'll spend
但包含多列數據，並且是一個結構你將要
the majority of your time working with when cleaning and aggregating data.
用大部分時間使用來清理和聚合數據。
But before we move on to a discussion of the data frame, our tutorial assistant for
但我們討論的資料幀之前，我們助教
this course will provide a more in-depth look at how the series object can be used.
將提供更深入地看看如何可以使用系列物件。